ebird.org 2013-12-15

# Privacy Policy | eBird

eBird is designed to gather and disseminate information about bird distribution and abundance across the Western Hemisphere.

### Submitted Information

Personal Information is voluntarily supplied by you when you register and submit data to eBird. By registering, you allow us to associate your bird observations with a unique identifier (login name or your name), so that you can track your personal observations (e.g., life lists and backyard lists). If you submit an unusual observation, we may e-mail you to request more details, but your email address and contact information will not be sold or distributed outside the Cornell Lab of Ornithology, Audubon and eBird partners in regions where you are participating. Profile Information allows us to gain a better understanding of the eBird participants and to determine how best to improve the web site for eBird users.

Bird observations are the most important pieces of information that we collect. All details of an observation and its associated location (species, numbers, etc.) are available to all users registered with eBird. However, only information pertaining to bird observations is available to eBird users; no personal contact information is ever made public.

### Sensitive Species

Because a primary goal of eBird is to maintain a universally accessible, centralized database of bird observations, the bird observations you submit are available to all eBird users (eBirders), scientists, and others who are interested in examining the distribution, abundance, and trends of North American bird species.

eBirders are able to view their personal observations and the observations of others, so please be aware that your observations of sensitive species and their locations will be available to other eBird users.

As conservation organizations, the Cornell Lab of Ornithology and the National Audubon Society seek to limit disturbance to birds especially at sensitive locations such as nest and roost sites. If you are not familiar with the American Birding Association’s [Principles of Birding Ethics](http://www.aba.org/about/ethics.html), we encourage you to review them.

### Cookies

Cookies are pieces of data that we store on your computer to tie your information to the eBird program. Cookies allow you to store your login information, so that you will not be required to log in each time you visit the eBird web site.

Internet browsers allow you to determine whether or not to accept cookies (check under the preferences or options in the browser menu). If you decide not to accept cookies, you can still use the eBird site, but you will need to re-enter login information each time you visit.

### Great Backyard Bird Count

Participants in the Great Backyard Bird Count may wish to review the [GBBC privacy policy](http://www.birdsource.org/gbbc/faqs-1/privacy) as well.

### Changes to This Privacy Policy

We may occasionally update or amend eBird’s Privacy Statement. If we make changes, we will post the changes here.
